How far would you go to escape the past?
The Human Stain is a drama, romance film directed by Robert Benton.
Coleman Silk is a worldly and admired professor who loses his
job after unwittingly making a racial slur.
To clear his name, Silk writes a book about the events with his friend and colleague Nathan
Zuckerman, who in the process discovers a dark secret Silk has hidden his whole life.
All the while, Silk engages in an affair with Faunia Farley, a younger woman whose
tormented past threatens to unravel the layers of deception Silk has constructed.
Coleman Silk, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Faunia Farley, played by Nicole Kidman.
Lester Farley, played by Ed Harris.
Nathan Zuckerman, played by Gary Sinise.
Young Coleman Silk, played by Wentworth Miller.
Steena Paulsson, played by Jacinda Barrett.
The Human Stain is a 2003 American drama film directed by Robert Benton.
Its screenplay, by Nicholas Meyer, is based on the
novel of the same name by Philip Roth.
The film stars Anthony Hopkins, Nicole Kidman, Gary Sinise, and Ed Harris.
The tone is dark and emotional.